Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And my name is Katrin.
我叫Katrin。
And today we've got a very, very useful lesson for all of you out there.
今天，我们为大家带来了一节非常非常实用的课程。
That's right.
没错。
We're bringing you part two of the What If series, which is a small series.
我们带来了“如果”系列的第二部分，这是一个小系列。
Small.
小系列。
And it is kind of grammar focused, but it's very, very important because you often want
它有点侧重语法，但非常非常重要，因为你经常想
to talk about things that don't happen.
谈论那些没有发生的事情。
We're calling these hypotheticals or conditional statements.
我们称之为假设句或条件句。
Right.
对。
And there are different types of hypotheticals or conditional statements.
假设句或条件句有不同的类型。
So today we're going to be looking at the third conditional, which is probably the hardest
所以今天我们要学习第三条件句，这可能是最难
one because it uses a little bit of a complex grammar structure.
的一种，因为它用到了稍微复杂的语法结构。
It's complex and we're actually talking about things that did not happen and that will not
它很复杂，而且我们实际上在谈论那些没有发生、也不会
happen, right?
发生的事情，对吧？
It's impossible to change.
这些是无法改变的。
It's impossible to change these because there are things that would have happened in the
这些是无法改变的，因为它们是过去本会发生
past but didn't.
却没有发生的事情。
Wow, that sounds confusing.
哇，听起来好复杂。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the first time and then we'll be back to look
我们为什么不先听一遍对话，然后再回来看看
at some phrases first.
一些短语呢？
This is the good life.
这就是美好生活。
We have it good, don't you think?
我们过得很好，你不觉得吗？
Yeah, of course.
是啊，当然。
Although, don't you ever wonder what could have been?
不过，你难道没想过本可能是什么样子吗？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Well, sometimes I think of how things could have turned out if I had done things a little
嗯，有时候我会想，如果我当初做得稍微
differently.
不同一点，事情会变成什么样。
For example?
比如呢？
Like, for example, if I hadn't studied architecture, I would have become an artist like I wanted
比如，如果我没有学建筑，我就会成为我想成为的
to.
艺术家。
I see.
我明白了。
Yeah, now that I think of it, I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved to this
是啊，现在想想，如果我没有搬到这个镇子
town and met Sally.
遇到Sally，我就不会结婚。
You see, everything happens for a reason.
你看，一切事情的发生都有原因。
We wouldn't even have met if I hadn't been in that car accident ten years ago.
如果十年前我没有出那场车祸，我们甚至都不会相遇。
Well, I have no regrets.
嗯，我没什么遗憾。
I'll drink to that.
我为此干杯。
All right, so two guys, you know, talking about life.
好了，两个男人在谈论生活。
I imagine these guys as being, you know, middle age or a little bit older, sitting on a porch,
我想象这两个人大概是中年或稍微年长一点，坐在门廊上，
drinking a beer, talking about what could have been.
喝着啤酒，谈论着本可能发生的事。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
They're kind of thinking about the past and the decisions they have made.
他们有点在回想过去和他们做出的决定。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
All right, so before we start in the grammar, why don't we take a look at a couple of different
好了，在我们开始讲语法之前，我们先来看看
phrases on Fluency Builder.
流利度提升器里的几个不同短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升器。
Well, Marco, this first phrase is a phrase you'll hear very often in English.
嗯，Marco，第一个短语是你在英语中经常听到的。
It's a phrase that even has philosophical roots, something we talked a lot about when
这个短语甚至带有哲学根源，我们在学校学苏格拉底时
we were studying Socrates back in school.
经常讨论这个。
But this is the good life.
但这就是“美好生活”。
The good life.
“美好生活”。
We have the good life or I have a good life.
我们过着美好生活，或者我过着美好生活。
I have a good life is a very common phrase, but here the good life is an idiom.
“我过着美好生活”是一个很常见的短语，但这里的“美好生活”是一个习语。
So I'm living the good life.
所以我在享受美好生活。
It means, you know, I have no complaints about my life.
它的意思是，我对生活没什么可抱怨的。
Right, so pretty much you have all your necessities covered.
对，基本上你所有的基本需求都满足了。
And maybe you have a good, a nice family and you have a good job and you're just happy.
也许你有一个好家庭，一份好工作，你很快乐。
So this is the good life.
所以这就是美好生活。
Very good.
很好。
So you have the good life.
所以你过着美好生活。
Now moving on to another phrase that's kind of also philosophical, you know, it says everything
现在来看另一个也有点哲学意味的短语，它说“一切事情
happens for a reason.
的发生都有原因”。
All right.
好的。
So this phrase is, well, it's also pretty common.
这个短语也很常见。
People say this when bad things happen, but they also say this when good things happen.
人们在坏事发生时这么说，但好事发生时也这么说。
Yeah.
是啊。
So basically you're just saying that it's destiny.
所以基本上你是在说这是命运。
If this bad thing happened to you, there is a reason for it.
如果这件坏事发生在你身上，那是有原因的。
Maybe you don't see it now, maybe not tomorrow, but maybe later you'll see why.
也许你现在看不到，也许明天也看不到，但以后你会明白为什么。
This often happens when people lose their jobs.
这经常发生在人们失业的时候。
You say, well, you know, everything happens for a reason.
你会说，嗯，你知道，一切事情的发生都有原因。
Maybe losing this job will allow you to find a better job.
也许失去这份工作会让你找到更好的工作。
Or maybe go back to school and study.
或者回学校学习。
Or maybe meet the man or woman of your dreams.
或者遇到你梦想中的男人或女人。
Right.
对。
So everything happens for a reason.
所以一切事情的发生都有原因。
Very good.
很好。
And then the guy agrees and says, well, I'll drink to that.
然后那个人表示同意，说，嗯，我为此干杯。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a way for people speaking English to say, listen, I agree with you.
这是说英语的人表达“听着，我同意你”的一种方式。
I like that idea and I will, cheers.
我喜欢这个想法，我会，干杯。
Cheers.
干杯。
Right.
对。
So this means we're going to touch our glasses or touch our beer bottles and we're going
所以这意味着我们要碰杯或碰啤酒瓶，然后
to, you know, think about how this is a, it's a nice thought, you know, everything happens
想想这是个好想法，你知道，一切事情的发生
for a reason is positive.
都有原因是积极的。
It's a way to say, listen, good things can happen from this.
这是一种说“听着，好事可以从中发生”的方式。
So he's saying, yes, I agree.
所以他在说，是的，我同意。
Cheers.
干杯。
I'll drink to that.
我为此干杯。
All right.
好的。
Well, pretty interesting phrases.
嗯，这些短语挺有意思的。
You know, they're very common, I guess, like colloquial, right?
你知道，它们很常见，我想，算是口语化的，对吧？
So you can use them in everyday conversation with a friend.
所以你可以在日常和朋友聊天时使用它们。
You can.
可以。
And, you know, oftentimes we say, for example, something really positive, like, I'm really
而且，你知道，我们经常说，比如，一些非常积极的话，比如“我真的很
glad I have such great friends.
高兴我有这么好的朋友”。
And then everyone says, oh, I'll drink to that.
然后每个人都说，哦，我为此干杯。
Right.
对。
So this is something you'll hear when you're out with friends or with family.
所以这是你和朋友或家人出去时会听到的。
And they may sound funny at first, but you will recognize them when you're speaking to
一开始可能听起来有点奇怪，但当你和说英语的人
people who speak English.
交谈时，你会认出它们的。
All right.
好的。
So, all right.
那么，好了。
So let's listen to our dialogue again and then we'll come back and explain the grammar.
让我们再听一遍对话，然后回来解释语法。
This is the good life.
这就是美好生活。
We have it good, don't you think?
我们过得很好，你不觉得吗？
Yeah, of course.
是啊，当然。
Although don't you ever wonder what could have been?
不过，你难道没想过本可能是什么样子吗？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Well, sometimes I think of how things could have turned out if I had done things a little
嗯，有时候我会想，如果我当初做得稍微
differently.
不同一点，事情会变成什么样。
For example?
比如呢？
Like, for example, if I hadn't studied architecture, I would have become an artist like I wanted
比如，如果我没有学建筑，我就会成为我想成为的
to.
艺术家。
I see.
我明白了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Now that I think of it, I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved to this town and
现在想想，如果我没有搬到这个镇上，
met Sally.
遇到莎莉，我就不会结婚了。
You see, everything happens for a reason.
你看，一切都有原因。
We wouldn't even have met if I hadn't been in that car accident ten years ago.
如果十年前我没有出那场车祸，我们甚至都不会相遇。
Well, I have no regrets.
嗯，我没什么遗憾。
I'll drink to that.
我为此干杯。
Beep, beep, beep.
哔，哔，哔。
All right.
好了。
So now it's time for grammar breakdown.
现在是语法解析时间。
Grammar breakdown.
语法解析。
So in grammar breakdown, we're going to look at the two main parts of these phrases that
在语法解析中，我们要看这些短语的两个主要部分，
allow us to talk about things that didn't happen.
它们让我们谈论没有发生的事情。
So we're talking about looking back at our life and seeing what decisions and what actions
我们在回顾自己的生活，看看我们做了哪些决定和行动。
we made.
我们做了哪些决定和行动。
And in this case, we have a great sentence here.
这里有一个很好的句子。
If I hadn't studied architecture, I would have become an artist.
如果我没有学建筑，我就会成为一名艺术家。
All right.
好了。
So let's look at the first part before the comma.
我们先看逗号前的第一部分。
If I hadn't studied architecture, so now we have the conditional if.
如果我没有学建筑，这里用了条件词“if”。
So Marco, big question.
那么，Marco，一个大问题。
Did he study architecture?
他学建筑了吗？
He did.
他学了。
So if I hadn't studied architecture, it means I did study architecture.
所以“如果我没有学建筑”意味着我确实学了建筑。
But if I had not studied it, okay, so this is if I could change the past, then what would
但如果我没有学，好吧，这是说如果我能改变过去，那么我会
I have done?
做什么呢？
I would have become an artist.
我会成为一名艺术家。
Okay.
好的。
So he wanted to be an artist, but he didn't become an artist.
所以他本来想当艺术家，但他没有成为艺术家。
He studied architecture instead.
他转而学了建筑。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
You can see the two parts here.
你可以看到这里有两个部分。
We have one, the condition, if I hadn't done this thing.
一个是条件：如果我没有做这件事。
And then afterwards, we have the result, then I would have become an artist.
然后后面是结果：那么我就会成为一名艺术家。
So this is the hypothetical.
这就是假设。
Very good.
很好。
And when we see the condition, you see the structure of the sentence is had plus verb
当我们看到条件时，句子的结构是“had”加动词的
in past participle.
过去分词。
So if I hadn't studied architecture, and this is called the past perfect, right?
所以“如果我没有学建筑”，这叫做过去完成时，对吧？
And then the result, as you said, would have become, this is the present perfect, have
然后结果，如你所说，“would have become”，这是现在完成时，“have”
or has plus verb in past participle.
或“has”加动词的过去分词。
Let's look at another example.
我们来看另一个例子。
I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved to this town.
如果我没有搬到这个镇上，我就不会结婚。
Okay.
好的。
So we've got the same idea here, but we've got it flipped.
这里也是同样的意思，但顺序颠倒了。
We've got these two parts in different places.
这两个部分放在了不同的位置。
And so he's pretty much saying, if I hadn't moved to this town, then I wouldn't have gotten
他基本上是在说：如果我没有搬到这个镇上，那么我就不会
married.
结婚。
But what did happen?
但实际发生了什么？
He did move to this town and he did get married.
他确实搬到了这个镇上，也确实结婚了。
Exactly.
没错。
So then, yeah, like you say, he changed the condition and you can do this.
所以，就像你说的，他改变了条件，你可以这样做。
You can put the condition in the beginning or at the end.
你可以把条件放在开头或结尾。
And again, the structure is the same.
同样，结构是一样的。
I would have gotten married, right?
“I would have gotten married”，对吧？
Have gotten, this is present perfect, have or has, depending on the subject, plus the
“Have gotten”是现在完成时，“have”或“has”取决于主语，加上
verb in past participle.
动词的过去分词。
And then the past perfect or the condition, had plus verb in past participle, hadn't moved
然后过去完成时或条件，“had”加动词的过去分词，“hadn't moved”
to this town.
“to this town”。
All right.
好了。
That's a lot of grammar.
语法真多啊。
It's a lot of grammar, but it's very easy once you just start using it.
语法是很多，但一旦开始用起来就很简单了。
Don't think too much about, okay, what do I do here?
别想太多，比如“我该怎么做？”
Just, you know, if you get the rhythm and you start using it in the same way, then it
只要，你知道，如果你掌握了节奏，开始以同样的方式使用它，那么它
kind of comes out naturally.
就会自然地说出来。
And if you make a little mistake, there's not a big deal because even we do it, you
如果你犯点小错，也没什么大不了的，因为连我们也会犯，
know?
你知道吗？
Exactly.
没错。
Well, let's try a couple of examples off the top of our heads.
好吧，我们随口试几个例子。
First of all, if I hadn't moved to China, I wouldn't have learned Chinese.
首先，如果我没有搬到中国，我就不会学中文。
Very good.
很好。
So you did move to China and you did learn Chinese.
所以你确实搬到了中国，也确实学了中文。
Exactly.
没错。
So your turn.
轮到你了。
All right.
好了。
If my parents hadn't spoken Spanish to me when I was a kid, I wouldn't have become fluent
如果我小时候父母没有跟我说西班牙语，我就不会流利地
in Spanish.
说西班牙语。
Okay.
好的。
So your parents did speak Spanish to you and you did become fluent in Spanish.
所以你父母确实跟你说了西班牙语，你也确实流利地说了西班牙语。
So not bad.
不错。
Right.
对。
So maybe you can use it not only to think about things in the past that you can't change
所以你可以用它不仅来思考过去无法改变的事情，
anymore, but just also, you know, kind of remember or say, you know, oh, if this hadn't
还可以，你知道，回忆或说，哦，如果这没有
happened, the result.
发生，结果会怎样。
Or if I hadn't opened my big mouth, my best friend wouldn't have gotten so angry at me.
或者如果我没有多嘴，我最好的朋友就不会对我那么生气了。
Exactly.
没错。
So I said something stupid and my friend did get angry and now I feel bad about it.
所以我说了蠢话，我的朋友确实生气了，现在我觉得很内疚。
It happens.
这种事常有。
All right.
好了。
Very good.
很好。
So I hope it's clear.
希望这很清楚。
It does sound a little bit complicated, but this is what our website is for, right?
听起来有点复杂，但这就是我们网站的用途，对吧？
So if you have questions or doubts or you want to try and plant your own ideas, you
所以如果你有问题或疑问，或者想尝试表达自己的想法，你
can come to the website and do it.
可以来网站做。
Want to make some of your own sentences and practice some of these new things, then come
想自己造些句子，练习这些新内容，那就来
to our website, post some comments and we are happy to correct and add our own commentary
我们的网站，发表评论，我们很乐意纠正并添加我们自己的评论
on those.
在上面。
Exactly.
没错。
So before we go, let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
所以在结束前，让我们再听一遍这段对话。
This is the good life.
这就是好生活。
You have it good, don't you think?
你过得不错，你不觉得吗？
Yeah, of course.
是啊，当然。
Although, don't you ever wonder what could have been?
不过，你难道没想过可能会是什么样吗？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Well, sometimes I think of how things could have turned out if I had done things a little
嗯，有时我会想，如果我做事稍微不同，事情会变成
differently.
什么样。
For example?
比如？
Like, for example, if I hadn't studied architecture, I would have become an artist like I wanted
比如，如果我没有学建筑，我就会像我想要的那样成为一名艺术家
to.
了。
I see.
我明白了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Now that I think of it, I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved to this town and
现在想想，如果我没有搬到这个镇上，
met Sally.
遇到莎莉，我就不会结婚了。
You see, everything happens for a reason.
你看，一切都有原因。
We wouldn't even have met if I hadn't been in that car accident 10 years ago.
如果十年前我没有出那场车祸，我们甚至都不会相遇。
Well, I have no regrets.
嗯，我没什么遗憾。
I'll drink to that.
我同意。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, Catherine, any other regrets maybe in your life apart from opening your mouth?
那么，凯瑟琳，除了开口说话之外，你生活中还有其他遗憾吗？
Any other regrets?
还有其他遗憾吗？
If my parents had spoken Spanish to me as a kid, I would have learned.
如果我小时候我父母跟我说西班牙语，我早就学会了。
But instead, I just learned English and that's all.
但相反，我只学了英语，就这些。
Well, your mom is half Swedish, right?
嗯，你妈妈有一半瑞典血统，对吧？
Half Swedish, half Czech.
一半瑞典，一半捷克。
And she never spoke any of these languages to you?
她从来没跟你说过这些语言吗？
No, she didn't speak Swedish or Czech.
没有，她不说瑞典语或捷克语。
Her parents spoke English as their common language, but she grew up speaking Italian
她的父母用英语作为共同语言，但她从小讲意大利语
and German.
和德语。
But she didn't speak to me in those languages.
但她没跟我说过那些语言。
And then as an adult, she forgot some of them.
然后成年后，她忘了一些。
And so, because my dad was, well, they're both Americans now, but my dad's American.
所以，因为我爸爸是，嗯，他们现在都是美国人，但我爸爸是美国人。
They just spoke English to me.
他们只跟我说英语。
Wow.
哇。
But now you speak Italian.
但现在你会说意大利语。
So, do you ever try and talk to your mom in Italian?
那你有没有试着跟你妈妈用意大利语聊天？
Sometimes.
有时候。
My grandmother's Italian is much better.
我奶奶的意大利语好多了。
So, my grandmother is completely fluent.
所以，我奶奶完全流利。
So I speak to her in Italian and German as well.
所以我也用意大利语和德语跟她说话。
She's fluent in German too.
她德语也很流利。
And I studied German at school.
我在学校学过德语。
See, this is the interesting thing now.
看，现在有趣的是这个。
So many people are speaking so many languages.
这么多人会讲这么多语言。
Even before, if you spoke another foreign language, it was a big deal.
以前，如果你会说一门外语，那就算大事了。
Oh yeah.
哦，是啊。
But now it's like a requirement.
但现在这就像个要求。
You have to at least dominate your own native language and a foreign language, right?
你至少得掌握自己的母语和一门外语，对吧？
So, if your native language is English, you at least have to speak Spanish or Chinese
所以，如果你的母语是英语，你至少得会说西班牙语或中文
or some other language.
或其他语言。
Definitely true.
确实如此。
And I think there are a lot of people, a lot of our users that speak maybe two or three
而且我觉得有很多人，很多我们的用户，可能会说两三种
languages and English is just one more.
语言，而英语只是其中一种。
So, you know, more power to them.
所以，你知道，他们真厉害。
This is a really great skill to have and I think it's really important to keep on going
这是一项很棒的能力，我觉得坚持下去很重要，
with it even though it's frustrating sometimes.
即使有时候很让人沮丧。
And actually, once you've been able, and actually once you mastered two or three different languages,
而且实际上，一旦你能，一旦你掌握了两三种不同的语言，
then the fourth and fifth just becomes easier.
那么第四种和第五种就变得更容易了。
Actually it's true.
其实是真的。
It sounds funny when you hear it because you're like, how could it be easier to learn more?
听起来有点好笑，因为你会想，怎么能更容易学更多呢？
But your brain starts to understand patterns better, right?
但你的大脑开始更好地理解模式，对吧？
And so it just becomes more natural for you.
所以对你来说就变得更自然了。
It just picks up patterns from the two or three other different languages that you dominate.
它只是从你掌握的两三种其他不同语言中提取模式。
So it's a weird, it's strange how the brain works.
所以这很奇怪，大脑的运作方式很奇妙。
You make connections.
你会建立联系。
Yeah.
是啊。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
So that's all for today.
今天就到这里。
Be sure to visit our website EnglishPod.com.
一定要访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
As we said, any questions or comments or you want us to correct your grammar of this lesson,
就像我们说的，有任何问题或评论，或者你想让我们纠正这课语法，
you can visit us there and we'll see you guys next time.
你可以在那里找我们，我们下次再见。
All right.
好的。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Special thanks topopular Editor Scotton McCray for en regulating Englishijn.com.
特别感谢热门编辑 Scotton McCray 对 Englishijn.com 的规范。